Thomas Moore Papers
Thomas Moore Papers
1983-2010
Moore, Thomas, 1940-
11.5 linear ft.
American author and psychotherapist, author of Care of the Soul and others. Collection contains audiovisual material, correspondence, manuscripts, memorabilia, and writings.
2746181
Biographical History
Thomas Moore (1940-) is an American author, most known for his popular books on spirituality. He has master's degrees in musicology (University of Michigan) and theology (University of Windsor, Ontario), and a PhD in religion (Syracuse University). Over the course of his life he has been a monk, a musician, a university professor, an author, and a psychotherapist; his books include the New York Times bestseller Care of the Soul (1992). He is a regular columnist for The Huffington Post and Spirituality and Health magazine. With Jean Hinson-Lall, he co-founded the Institute for the Study of Imagination.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Thomas Moore Papers contains audiovisual material, correspondence, manuscripts, memorabilia, and writings.
Audiovisual material consists of commercially-produced audio versions of Moore's books, appearances by Moore on various radio and television shows and specials, workshops and other hosted productions, and other items.
Correspondence contains both personal and professional, including colleagues in the fields of psychotherapy, psychology and spirituality (Clarissa Pinkola Estes, Suzi Gablik, Annie Gottlieb, the New York Center for Jungian Studies, George Nickelsburg, Ronald Schenk, Joanne Stroud), publishers (Bantam Books, Harper Collins, Larson Publications, Shepherd-Walwyn), magazines for whom Moore wrote ( L'Immaginale, Journeymen, The Salt Journal, Spirituality and Health), and journalists (Bill Moyers). There are also numerous letters from readers of his best-selling book Care of the Soul.
Manuscripts contains early drafts, proofs, and setting copy of The Soul of Sex (1998).
Memorabilia includes catalogs in which Moore's works were sold, clippings, and publicity related to his books.
Writings contains published books (including numerous foreign-language editions) and book chapters; forewords, prefaces, and introductions; interviews; journal, magazine, and newspaper articles, and a few miscellaneous items.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically by type or title.
Subject and Genre Headings
Religion and philosophy; Moore, Thomas, 1940-; Authors, American.; Psychology, Religious.; Psychotherapists -- United States.; Spiritual life -- United States.; Audiobooks.; Audiocassettes.; Books.; Clippings (information artifacts); Compact discs.; Correspondence.; Interviews.; Magazines (periodicals); Manuscripts for publication.; Reviews (documents); Videocassettes.; Psychotherapists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Thomas Moore, 2001-2002.
Inventory
- Audiovisual material
  - Audiobooks, commercially produced audio versions of books by Moore
    - The Art of Simplicity, Thomas Moore (14080A) (1 of 5), moore_t_115; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
      Session 1: The Richness in Simple Pleasures; Session 2: A Sense of Community
    - The Art of Simplicity, Thomas Moore (14080A) (2 of 5), moore_t_116; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
      Session 3: Emptying Out; Session 4: The Fantasy of Busyness
    - The Art of Simplicity, Thomas Moore (14080A) (3 of 5), moore_t_117; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
      Session 5: The Spirit and Soul of Simplicity; Session 6: An Attitude of Acceptance
    - The Art of Simplicity, Thomas Moore (14080A) (4 of 5), moore_t_118; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
      Session 7: Entering Life More Fully; Session 8: Simplicity through the Ages
    - The Art of Simplicity, Thomas Moore (14080A) (5 of 5), moore_t_119; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
      Bonus Cassette: 10 Suggestions for Making Life Simple
    - The Art of Simplicity, Thomas Moore (14080A) [copy 2] (1 of 5), moore_t_120; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - The Art of Simplicity, Thomas Moore (14080A) [copy 2] (2 of 5), moore_t_121; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - The Art of Simplicity, Thomas Moore (14080A) [copy 2] (3 of 5), moore_t_122; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - The Art of Simplicity, Thomas Moore (14080A) [copy 2] (4 of 5), moore_t_123; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - The Art of Simplicity, Thomas Moore (14080A) [copy 2] (5 of 5), moore_t_124; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Care of the Soul by Thomas Moore (94373) (1 of 9), moore_t_098; unabridged audiobook set of nine cassettes/12.25 hours by arrangements with HarperCollins Publishers Inc.; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Care of the Soul by Thomas Moore (94373) (2 of 9), moore_t_099; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Care of the Soul by Thomas Moore (94373) (3 of 9), moore_t_100; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Care of the Soul by Thomas Moore (94373) (4 of 9), moore_t_101; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Care of the Soul by Thomas Moore (94373) (5 of 9), moore_t_102; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Care of the Soul by Thomas Moore (94373) (6 of 9), moore_t_103; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Care of the Soul by Thomas Moore (94373) (7 of 9), moore_t_104; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Care of the Soul by Thomas Moore (94373) (8 of 9), moore_t_105; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Care of the Soul by Thomas Moore (94373) (9 of 9), moore_t_106; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - The Education of the Heart (CPN 2593) (1 of 2), 10/11/1996; moore_t_084; readings and sources for "Care of the Soul", "Soul Mates", and "The Re-Enchantment of Everyday Life" selected by Moore; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 2)
    - The Education of the Heart (CPN 2593) (2 of 2), 10/11/1996; moore_t_085; readings and sources for "Care of the Soul", "Soul Mates", and "The Re-Enchantment of Everyday Life" selected by Moore; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 2)
    - A Magical Life by Thomas Moore (1 of 2), moore_t_082; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - A Magical Life by Thomas Moore (2 of 2), moore_t_083; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Meditations: On the Monk Who Dwell in Daily Life (CPN10053), 8/14/1994; moore_t_079; Audiobook on cassette performed by the author. Includes paper box with HarperAudio flyer advertising with other published materials.; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 80:00 (Box 2)
    - The Re-Enchantment of Everyday Life (CPN 2569) (1 of 2), 02/14/1996; moore_t_086; abridged audiobook on two cassettes; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 2)
    - The Re-Enchantment of Everyday Life (CPN 2569) (2 of 2), 02/14/1996; moore_t_087; abridged audiobook on two cassettes; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 2)
    - Soul Mates by Thomas Moore (94462) (1 of 8), moore_t_107; unabridged audiobook set of eight cassettes/10.75 hours by arrangements with HarperCollins Publishers Inc.; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Soul Mates by Thomas Moore (94462) (2 of 8), moore_t_108; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Soul Mates by Thomas Moore (94462) (3 of 8), moore_t_109; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Soul Mates by Thomas Moore (94462) (4 of 8), moore_t_110; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Soul Mates by Thomas Moore (94462) (5 of 8), moore_t_111; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Soul Mates by Thomas Moore (94462) (6 of 8), moore_t_112; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Soul Mates by Thomas Moore (94462) (7 of 8), moore_t_113; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Soul Mates by Thomas Moore (94462) (8 of 8), moore_t_114; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - The Thomas Moore Audio Collection (BGS004) (1 of 4), January 2 and 3, 1992; moore_t_094; audiobooks "Care of the Soul" and "Soul Mates"; includes HarperAudio flyer advertising with other published materials; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 3)
      Tape 1: Care of the Soul (CPN2298) - A Guide for Cultivating Depth and Sacredness in Everyday Life
    - The Thomas Moore Audio Collection (BGS004) (2 of 4), January 2 and 3, 1992; moore_t_095; audiobooks "Care of the Soul" and "Soul Mates"; includes HarperAudio flyer advertising with other published materials; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 3)
      Tape 2: Care of the Soul (CPN2298) - A Guide for Cultivating Depth and Sacredness in Everyday Life
    - The Thomas Moore Audio Collection (BGS004) (3 of 4), October 20, 1993; moore_t_096; audiobooks "Care of the Soul" and "Soul Mates"; includes HarperAudio flyer advertising with other published materials; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 88:00 (Box 3)
      Tape 1: Soul Mates (CPN2419): Honoring the Mysteries of Love and Relationship
    - The Thomas Moore Audio Collection (BGS004) (4 of 4), October 20, 1993; moore_t_097; audiobooks "Care of the Soul" and "Soul Mates"; includes HarperAudio flyer advertising with other published materials; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 88:00 (Box 3)
      Tape 2: Soul Mates (CPN2419): Honoring the Mysteries of Love and Relationship
    - Thomas Moore on Meaningful Work (A340) (1 of 2), moore_t_090; audiobook on 2 cassettes; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 94:00 (Box 2)
    - Thomas Moore on Meaningful Work (A340) (2 of 2), moore_t_091; audiobook on 2 cassettes; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 94:00 (Box 2)
    - Thomas Moore on Writing (A343) (1 of 2), moore_t_092; audiobook on 2 cassettes; "Soul Life" book is advertised on the cassette's insert; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 96:00 (Box 3)
    - Thomas Moore on Writing (A343) (2 of 2), moore_t_093; audiobook on 2 cassettes; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 96:00 (Box 3)
  - Interviews and guest appearances, most of these are homemade tapes, recorded off radio or television
    - Booklights, Thomas Moore, 7/20/96; moore_t_055; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 2)
    - Conversation with Leonard Lopate featuring Thomas Moore, "The Soul of Sex", moore_t_078; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - A Conversation with Thomas Moore, moore_t_010; Video includes Pledge breaks.; VHS; running time 1:02:40 (Box 1)
    - A Conversation with Thomas Moore (rough cut), 12/21/94; moore_t_011; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
    - A Conversation with Thomas Moore (WSP 124), 1994-1995; moore_t_034; As Seen on Public Television. For non-commercial private exhibition in homes. Features Thomas Moore, author of Care the Soul and Soul Mates, in a wide ranging conversation with writer Valerie Andrews.; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
    - Discussion with ... Thomas Moore: "Honoring the Mysteries of Love and Relationship" interviewed by Jack Cole, 1/24/1994; moore_t_007; VHS; running time 29:15 (Box 1)
    - Dr. Thomas Moore Revealing Secrets for Mind and Body, host Andrea Candee, moore_t_075; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Faces on Faith Live with Thomas Moore, hosted by Linda Hanick, 10/10/1993; moore_t_001; VHS; running time 1:25:30 (Box 1)
    - Good Morning America: Dreams, 2/3/95; moore_t_014; VHS (Box 1)
    - Good Morning America: The Gift of Poetry, 12-8-94; moore_t_009; Andy Carroll also appears on the show; VHS; running time 30:00 (Box 1)
    - HB Pictures: "A Conversation with Thomas Moore" (non-broadcast version), 1/20/95; moore_t_012; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
    - HB Pictures: "A Conversation with Thomas Moore" (PBS Pledge version), 1/20/95; moore_t_013; VHS; running time 61:00 (Box 1)
    - Innerwisdom with Carolyn Craft, guest Thomas Moore, moore_t_077; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 2)
    - Jean Feraca: "Meditations" by Thomas Moore, 1/15/94; 1995; moore_t_047; Wisconsin Public Radio program: "Conversations with Jean Feraca"; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Jean Feraca: Crass Commercialism, Thomas Moore, 12/26/94; 1995; moore_t_049; Wisconsin Public Radio program: "Conversations with Jean Feraca"; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Jean Feraca: The Role of Magic in Modern Life, Thomas Moore, 1993; 6/09/94; moore_t_048; Wisconsin Public Radio program: "Conversations with Jean Feraca"; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - God Series: Thomas Moore, 12/10/96; moore_t_019; morning program; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
    - JBS Program 8/11-8/12; 12-1: Thomas Moore, moore_t_074; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - KHOW [Denver] Thomas Moore: Care of the Soul, moore_t_076; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 26:46 (Box 2)
    - KUSF [University of San Francisco], 03/08/2000; moore_t_070; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 2)
    - The Marc Steiner Show: Thomas Moore, 03/13/2000; moore_t_071; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - The McCuistion Program: Searching for the Soul in Business, moore_t_006; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
    - [New Dimensions?], 1991; moore_t_058; cassette has no labels; insert features New Dimensions tapes containing weekly interviews; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:0 (Box 2)
    - New Dimensions No. 2448: Thomas Merton the Man with Ron Seitz, No. 2448, 1996-1997; moore_t_060; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - New Dimensions No. 2476: Thomas Merton Remembered, No. 2476, 1996; moore_t_061; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - New Dimensions No. 2484: Anne Stirling Hastings, 1996; moore_t_062; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - New Dimensions No. 2502: Thomas Moore, 1991-1994; moore_t_063; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 65:00 (Box 2)
    - New Dimensions No. 2810: Thomas Moore, Program No. 2810, 1997-03/08/00; moore_t_064; unedited tape for guest; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 64:00 (Box 2)
    - New Dimensions No. 5721: Highlights from "New Dimensions" Radio Interviews "Friends of New Dimensions", 1996-1997; moore_t_059; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - NPR: Midmorning, 03/22/2000; moore_t_072; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Prime Time Radio, June 18, 1996; June 25, 1996; moore_t_053; one-hour weekly interview program; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
      Side 1: Investing and Financial Planning; Re-enchanting Everyday Life; Side 2: The Murrow Boys; Widower
    - Prime Time Radio, September 8, 1998; September 15, 1998; moore_t_054; one-hour weekly interview program; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
      Side 1: Sweepstakes; Storytelling; Side 2: Women's Health; Sex and the Soul
    - Quest: Energy Power Spirit (Z1008), 1997; moore_t_037; Breakthrough views of mind, body and healing. Participants in the production: Sarah Ban Breathnach, Caroline Myss, Bernie Siegel, David Whyte, Thomas Moore, Stephan Rechtschaffen, Marianne Williamson.; VHS; running time 58:00 (Box 1)
    - Quest: Light My Fire. The Art of Sacred and Ecstatic Lovemaking (Vol. 4), moore_t_038; A Lili Pournier Special. Participants in the production: Deepak Chopra, Barbara De Angelis, John Gray, Erica Jong, Sam Keen, Thomas Moore, Margot Anand, Kutira & Raphael.; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
    - Questions of Faith Pilot "Survival" with Eaton intro, moore_t_030; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
    - Syracuse University Library Associates: "A Conversation with Thomas Moore", 6/5/98; moore_t_027; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 1)
    - Thomas Moore MSNBC, 12/10/96; moore_t_020; VHS; running time 30:00 (Box 1)
    - Thomas Moore: "A mirror with a voice" (Master No. 2), moore_t_031; Green Table Productions video.; S-VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
    - The Thomas Pecora Show: Thomas Moore, PH.D., part 3, 06/05/2000; moore_t_073; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 2)
    - Who am I? Why am I here? (WSP 131), 1996; moore_t_035; Featuring Thomas Moore. For non-commercial private exhibition in homes.; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
  - Music, most of these are commercially produced tapes or CDs
    - Ludwig van Beethoven: Piano Concerti Nos. 1-5 (MHC 332660X), moore_t_129; commercial audio cassette of classical music; cassette No. 2, sides 3 and 4; includes insert; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 3)
    - Songs of the Soul, moore_t_032; VHS; running time 54:00 (Box 1)
    - The Soul of Christmas: A Celtic Music Celebration with Thomas Moore (UPAB1218) (1 of 2), moore_t_088; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 55:00 (Box 2)
      "The Words." Introduction; Thomas Moore on the soul of Christmas, with Celtic music producer Johnny Cunningham. Moore speaking about Christmas and its most important aspects, including the tree, the star the Virgin Mother and the divine child.
    - The Soul of Christmas: A Celtic Music Celebration with Thomas Moore (UPAB1218) (2 of 2), moore_t_089; Tape 2 features today's best Celtic musicians playing the season's loveliest carols. Songs for this project selected and arranged by Moore.; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 55:45 (Box 2)
      "The Music." 1: God Rest Ye Merry, Gentlemen; Jesus Christ, the Apple Tree; In Dulci Jubilo; We Three Kings; Silent Night; It Came Upon a Midnight Clear; I Saw Three Ships/Bells no Bells; In the Bleak Midwinter; Side 2: Lo, How a Rose; The Holly and the Ivy; Lully, Lullay; In Excelsis Deo; Remember O Thou Man; Christ Child's Lullaby
    - The Soul of Christmas: A Celtic Music Celebration with Thomas Moore (UPAB1218) (1 of 2), moore_t_126; CD; running time 55:00 (Box 3)
      "The Words." Introduction; Thomas Moore on the soul of Christmas, with Celtic music producer Johnny Cunningham. Moore speaking about Christmas and its most important aspects, including the tree, the star the Virgin Mother and the divine child. Includes 72-page booklet from author Thomas Moore.
    - The Soul of Christmas: A Celtic Music Celebration with Thomas Moore (UPAB1218) (2 of 2), moore_t_125; CD 2 features today's best Celtic musicians playing the season's loveliest carols. Songs for this project selected and arranged by Moore. Includes 72-page booklet from author Thomas Moore.; CD; running time 55:45 (Box 3)
      "The Music." 1. God Rest Ye Merry, Gentlemen; 2. Jesus Christ, the Apple Tree; 3. In Dulci Jubilo; 4. We Three Kings; 5. Silent Night; 6. It Came Upon a Midnight Clear; 7. I Saw Three Ships/Bells no Bells; 8. In the Bleak Midwinter; 9. Lo, How a Rose; 10. The Holly and the Ivy; 11. Lully, Lullay; 12. In Excelsis Deo; 13. Remember O Thou Man; 14. Christ Child's Lullaby
    - The Soul of Christmas: A Celtic music celebration with Thomas Moore (UPV1218), 1997; moore_t_039; Live Concert as Seen on Public Television. Copyright program.; VHS; running time 90:00 (Box 1)
    - The Soul of Christmas: A Celtic Music Celebration, 11/18/97; moore_t_026; PBS Special.; VHS; running time 58:30 (Box 1)
    - The Soul of Christmas: A Celtic Music Celebration with Thomas Moore, Off-Line Vers. 3, 11/05/97; moore_t_025; VHS; running time 59:00 (Box 1)
    - Thomas Moore: Music for the Soul: A Program for Re-Enchantment [copy 1], moore_t_127; A compilation CD with selections made by Thomas Moore. Multiple copyright owners. Includes CD insert with "exclusive new essay by Thomas Moore".; CD; running time 60:08 (Box 3)
      1. Alma Redemptoris Mater - Choir Of King's College, Cambridge/Stephen Cleobury; 2. Tu Solus Qui Facis Mirabilia - The Hilliard Ensemble/Paul Hillier; 3. Old And Lost Rivers - Houston Symphony Orchestra/Christoph Eschenbach; 4. Vespers-Ave Maria - Swedish Radio Choir/Tonu Kaljuste; 5. Cantus In Memory Of Benjamin Britten - Bournemouth Sinfonietta/Richard Studt; 6. Salve Regina - The Sixteen/Harry Christophers; 7. Fratres (Version VI) - London Philharmonic Orchestra/Franz Welser-Most; 8. Nuper Rosarum Flores - The Hilliard Ensemble/Paul Hillier; 9. Adagio - Saint Louis Symphony Orchestra/Leonard Slatkin; 10. Symphony No.3-Second Movement - Zofia Kilanowicz/ Szymanowski State Philharmonic Orchestra; Jacek Kasprzyk
    - Thomas Moore: Music for the Soul: A Program for Re-Enchantment [copy 2], moore_t_128; A compilation CD with selections made by Thomas Moore. Multiple copyright owners. Includes CD insert with "exclusive new essay by Thomas Moore".; CD; running time 60:08 (Box 3)
  - Workshops and hosted programs
    - Discovering Everyday Spirituality with Thomas Moore: Story, eight-part TV program; includes program summary; moore_t_002; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 1)
    - Discovering Everyday Spirituality with Thomas Moore: Place, eight-part TV program; includes program summary; moore_t_003; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 1)
    - Discovering Everyday Spirituality with Thomas Moore: Activity, eight-part TV program; includes program summary; moore_t_004; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 1)
    - Discovering Everyday Spirituality with Thomas Moore: Ritual, eight-part TV program; includes program summary; moore_t_036; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
    - DES [Discovering Everyday Spirituality]: Ritual, moore_t_005; comp. reel/ producers' segments; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
    - The New York Open Center: Care of the Soul workshop Tape 1, 11/14/92; moore_t_041; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - The New York Open Center: Care of the Soul workshop Tape 2, 11/14/92; moore_t_042; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - The New York Open Center: Care of the Soul workshop Tape 3, 11/14/92; moore_t_043; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - The New York Open Center: Care of the Soul workshop Tape 4, 11/14/92; moore_t_044; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - The New York Open Center: Care of the Soul workshop Tape 7, 11/13/92; moore_t_045; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Soul and Everyday Life (1 of 2), moore_t_080; lecture and workshop weekend conducted at The Open Center in New York; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 2)
      Side A: Evening Lecture; Side B: Evening Lecture (conclusion); Workshop
    - Soul and Everyday Life (2 of 2), moore_t_081; lecture and workshop weekend conducted at The Open Center in New York; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 2)
      Side A: Workshop (conclusion)
    - SoulWork: "Thomas Moore", 1998; moore_t_028; includes letter to Thomas Moore from Patricia Michael, SoulWork Producer, dated June, 9, 1998; VHS; running time 30:00 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, most of these are homemade tapes with handwritten labels
    - Citibank Credit Card Campaign, moore_t_033; VHS; running time 15:00 (Box 1)
    - First Person Desperately Seeking Happiness, 09/08/95; television program; Moore probably appeared on this, but cannot find a listing; moore_t_018; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 1)
    - From the Heart of New York: New York Open Center 10th Anniversary Sampler Tape, 1994; moore_t_046; Moore did several workshops at the New York Open Center; includes printed content list in the cassette insert; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Imagination in the Helping Profession: Tom Moore Tape 2, Spring 1983; moore_t_040; title on the cassette insert reads: "Beginner's Yoga"; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Institute for the Study of Imagination: On Inspiration, No. 162A (1 of 5), 1997; moore_t_065; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Institute for the Study of Imagination: On Inspiration, No. 162A (2 of 5), 1997; moore_t_066; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Institute for the Study of Imagination: On Inspiration, No. 162A (3 of 5), 1997; moore_t_067; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Institute for the Study of Imagination: On Inspiration, No. 162A (4 of 5), 1997; moore_t_068; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Institute for the Study of Imagination: On Inspiration, No. 162A (5 of 5), 1997; moore_t_069; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)
    - Kathleen Jenks: Woman's Way: Beyond the Hero (7 of 9), 4/12/97; collection has only 2 of the 9 tapes in this set; moore_t_056; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 2)